[
    {
        "question": "Which contributor to the Enlightenment identified two key aspects to our existence, liberty and property?",
        "options": ["John Locke", "Thomas Hobbes", "Montesquieu", "Adam Smith"],
        "correctAnswer": "John Locke"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the purpose of the Occupy Wall Street movement?",
        "options": [
            "It advocates for a correction of today's economic inequalities.",
            "It advocates for increased minority voting rights.",
            "It speaks out against the racial inequality in employment.",
            "It advocates for greater regulation of religious ideologies."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "It advocates for a correction of today's economic inequalities."
    },
    {
        "question": "There were several factors that significantly contributed to the government structure outlined in the Articles of Confederation. What was one of them?",
        "options": [
            "Americans wished the government to be representative of the states.",
            "The people wanted a strong central government to gather defenses in times of war.",
            "The states were unable to protect American ships from attacks by the Barbary pirates.",
            "Taxation was a well-recognized way for the national government to retain control over the individual states."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Americans wished the government to be representative of the states."
    },
    {
        "question": "What was a major difference between the Articles of Confederation and the Constitution?",
        "options": [
            "The Articles of Confederation required states to provide troops for national defense.",
            "The Articles of Confederation required states to pay for land claims west of the Appalachian Mountains.",
            "The Articles of Confederation did not provide for a national judiciary.",
            "The Articles of Confederation did not allow states to establish banks."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "The Articles of Confederation did not provide for a national judiciary."
    },
    {
        "question": "What did the Great Compromise between the Virginia Plan and the New Jersey Plan that was finalized in the Constitution establish?",
        "options": [
            "Authority to tax and regulate trade",
            "National armed forces",
            "A two-chamber Congress",
            "A national currency"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "A two-chamber Congress"
    },
    {
        "question": "What were the results of the three-fifths compromise?",
        "options": [
            "It required slave states to pay taxes on three-fifths of all imported enslaved persons.",
            "It allowed slave states to count three-fifths of their enslaved population for the purpose of representation.",
            "It required slave states to pay taxes on three-fifths of enslaved persons sold domestically.",
            "It allowed free states to pay taxes on only three-fifths of its foreign imports."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "It allowed slave states to count three-fifths of their enslaved population for the purpose of representation."
    },
    {
        "question": "What was a Federalist argument in support of the ratification of the Constitution?",
        "options": [
            "A strong national government is better for the representation of small landowners of modest wealth.",
            "A strong national government is better for national defense and economic growth.",
            "Strong state governments are better for funding internal improvements like roads.",
            "Strong state governments are better for facilitating business transactions."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "A strong national government is better for national defense and economic growth."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which concepts were James Madison referencing when he stated, 'Ambition must be made to counteract ambition' in Federalist, no. 51?",
        "options": [
            "Life and the pursuit of happiness",
            "Free enterprise and competition",
            "Equality and individual rights",
            "Separation of powers and checks and balances"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Separation of powers and checks and balances"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a judicial check on the executive branch?",
        "options": [
            "The Supreme Court can veto an executive order.",
            "The Supreme Court can declare actions by the executive branch unconstitutional.",
            "The Supreme Court can override an executive pardon.",
            "The Supreme Court can block a declaration of war."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "The Supreme Court can declare actions by the executive branch unconstitutional."
    },
    {
        "question": "What describes a legislative check on the judicial branch?",
        "options": [
            "Congress can limit the term of a Supreme Court justice.",
            "Congress can change the Supreme Court's jurisdiction.",
            "Congress can override a Supreme Court decision.",
            "Congress can appoint federal judges."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Congress can override a Supreme Court decision."
    },
    {
        "question": "What best explains why individual members of the Senate have more legislative power than individual members of the House of Representatives?",
        "options": [
            "The higher minimum age requirement in the Senate",
            "The ability of the Senate to approve members of the president's cabinet",
            "The increased length of the term of office in the Senate",
            "The smaller total number of Senate members compared to the number of representatives"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "The smaller total number of Senate members compared to the number of representatives"
    },
    {
        "question": "What describes the equal proportions method of congressional apportionment?",
        "options": [
            "Congressional districts are drawn in order to maintain similar numbers of voters in each district.",
            "Congressional districts are drawn to guarantee that each district will be equally represented in the Senate.",
            "Congressional districts are drawn so that states are each given an equal number of members in the House of Representatives.",
            "Congressional districts are drawn so each will have an equal number of members of the Republican and Democratic parties"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Congressional districts are drawn in order to maintain similar numbers of voters in each district."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is an example of a congressional allocation that would influence the national budget to help a member of congress's district or state?",
        "options": [
            "Money appropriated to specific projects that benefit a congressperson's personal businesses",
            "Funds for the building of an airport in a congressperson's district",
            "Exemptions written into the law that only benefit a certain political action committee",
            "A congressperson's support for a colleague's bill if the colleague will support the congresspersons's bill"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Funds for the building of an airport in a congressperson's district"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why is the House Rules Committee one of the most powerful committees in the U.S. House of Representatives?",
        "options": [
            "It defines the process of selecting the majority leader in the House of Representatives.",
            "It determines the rules for debate and in what order to schedule consideration of bills in the House.",
            "It sets rules that must be followed by both the House of Representatives and the Senate.",
            "It is made up of senior representatives who have served at least three terms in office."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "It determines the rules for debate and in what order to schedule consideration of bills in the House."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitutional amendment established term limits for the president?",
        "options": [
            "The Nineteenth Amendment",
            "The Twentieth Amendment",
            "The Twenty-Second Amendment",
            "The Seventeenth Amendment"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "The Twenty-Second Amendment"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the purpose of executive agreements?",
        "options": [
            "To exercise the use of the military without requiring a declaration of war from Congress",
            "To establish agreements with foreign countries without congressional approval",
            "To override congressional legislation that the president does not support",
            "To influence domestic policy without passing legislation through Congress"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "To establish agreements with foreign countries without congressional approval"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement best describes 'executive privilege'?",
        "options": [
            "When a president successfully asserts a power without impeachment, that power becomes assigned to the executive branch.",
            "A president may exercise any power because of the checks and balances provision by the other branches of government.",
            "A president may withhold confidential communication from the courts and the legislative branch.",
            "A president may expand power and authority through the use of the cabinet, which is not restricted or limited by the Constitution"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "A president may withhold confidential communication from the courts and the legislative branch."
    },
    {
        "question": "How can an outgoing president exert significant influence over a new president’s administration?",
        "options": [
            "By having a budget that affects the ability of the incoming administration to pursue new initiatives",
            "By continuing to operate through the first 100 days during the incoming administration's transition",
            "By reserving a seat in the new president's cabinet",
            "By participating in agenda setting during the transition"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "By participating in agenda setting during the transition"
    },
    {
        "question": "What describes the importance of the Supreme Court decision in Marbury v. Madison?",
        "options": [
            "It reinforced congressional impeachment power.",
            "It protected presidential control over the military.",
            "It established the principle of judicial review.",
            "It affirmed the presidential use of veto power."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "It established the principle of judicial review."
    },
    {
        "question": "How are individuals nominated to the Supreme Court?",
        "options": [
            "They are confirmed by the House of Representatives.",
            "They are chosen from the available constitutional law professors.",
            "They are selected from the current pool of federal judges.",
            "They are chosen by the president of the United States."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "They are chosen by the president of the United States."
    },
    {
        "question": "How does the 14th Amendment affect the powers of the federal judiciary?",
        "options": [
            "It expanded the judiciary’s power to rule in disputes between states.",
            "It expanded the judiciary’s power over states that applied laws unfairly.",
            "It restricted the judiciary’s power to national issues instead of state issues.",
            "It restricted the judiciary’s power to override state constitutions."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "It expanded the judiciary’s power over states that applied laws unfairly."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a power reserved for the states?",
        "options": [
            "Conducting foreign relations",
            "Declaring war",
            "Coining money",
            "Conducting elections"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Conducting elections"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitutional amendment allows states to reserve powers not explicitly granted to the national government?",
        "options": [
            "The Twelfth Amendment",
            "The Tenth Amendment",
            "The Nineteenth Amendment",
            "The Eighth Amendment"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "The Tenth Amendment"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did the Supreme Court's ruling in Gibbons v. Ogden establish?",
        "options": [
            "A loose constructionist interpretation of the commerce clause",
            "A strict constructionist interpretation of the supremacy clause",
            "A basis for exercising broad states' rights under the Tenth Amendment",
            "A foundation for the constitutional principle of judicial review"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "A loose constructionist interpretation of the commerce clause"
    },
    {
        "question": "How do most states award votes in the Electoral College?",
        "options": [
            "The candidate who wins the popular vote nationwide gets all the electoral votes for the state.",
            "The candidate who wins the popular vote in the state gets all the electoral votes for the state.",
            "Candidates get electoral votes in proportion to their share of the statewide popular vote.",
            "Candidates get one electoral vote for each congressional district where they win the popular vote."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "The candidate who wins the popular vote in the state gets all the electoral votes for the state."
    },

    {
        "question": "Which amendment provided for the separate election of the president and vice president?",
        "options": [
            "The Twelfth Amendment",
            "The Fourteenth Amendment",
            "The Eleventh Amendment",
            "The Thirteenth Amendment"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "The Twelfth Amendment"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a characteristic of an open primary system?",
        "options": [
            "Voters registered with any political party are allowed to vote for candidates in any party during the primary.",
            "Candidates from every political party compete against each other until two are selected for a general election.",
            "Voters are required to meet together to publicly declare their support for a primary candidate.",
            "Any resident in the district is allowed to run as a candidate for any party during the primary."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Voters registered with any political party are allowed to vote for candidates in any party during the primary."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is true about campaign ads in primary elections?",
        "options": [
            "They often discourage people from taking actions to vote.",
            "They are primarily aimed at more independent voters.",
            "They generally mention all participating political parties.",
            "They often try to raise the name recognition of a candidate."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "They often try to raise the name recognition of a candidate."
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the purpose of creating the Federal Election Commission in the 1970s?",
        "options": [
            "To manage the operation of polling stations",
            "To limit the influence of negative campaigning",
            "To ensure transparency in campaign financing",
            "To regulate the influence of super PACs"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "To ensure transparency in campaign financing"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who can vote for a United States representative?",
        "options": [
            "Any voter in the United States",
            "Any voter in the representative’s state",
            "Any voter in the representative’s congressional district",
            "Any voter registered in the representative’s party"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Any voter in the representative’s congressional district"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the definition of inside lobbying?",
        "options": [
            "An attempt to sway government decision-making targeted directly at government officials",
            "An attempt to sway government decision-making through media-covered events",
            "An attempt to sway government decision-making by proposing legislative policies",
            "An attempt to sway government decision-making by influencing public opinion"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "An attempt to sway government decision-making targeted directly at government officials"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was determined in U.S. v. Windsor and Obergefell v. Hodges?",
        "options": [
            "They declared DOMA unconstitutional and legalized same-sex marriage nationwide.",
            "They declared that spending money in an election was essentially equivalent to free speech.",
            "They removed any restrictive limits to how much money unions or corporations can donate to Super PACs.",
            "They required the registration of lobbyists representing any interest group under certain circumstances."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "They declared DOMA unconstitutional and legalized same-sex marriage nationwide."
    },
    {
        "question": "How do Super PACs operate?",
        "options": [
            "They cannot give money directly to individual candidates.",
            "They are allowed to give up to $15,000 per year to any national party.",
            "They collect money to donate to or against candidates or issues.",
            "They can give no more than $5000 per candidate, per election."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "They collect money to donate to or against candidates or issues."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is one common method of influence used by interest groups?",
        "options": [
            "They target the staff of opposing congressional members to educate them on relevant policy.",
            "They target cabinet members viewed as more sympathetic to their cause.",
            "They target members of congressional committees that have special influence on relevant legislative areas.",
            "They target celebrities and other highly influential figures to sway congressional voting."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "They target members of congressional committees that have special influence on relevant legislative areas."
    },
    {
        "question": "In which case did the Supreme Court establish that spending on political campaigns constituted political speech that is protected by the First Amendment?",
        "options": [
            "Shelby County v. Holder",
            "Buckley v. Valeo",
            "Breedlove v. Suttles",
            "Citizens United v. Federal Election Commission"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Citizens United v. Federal Election Commission"
    },

    {
        "question": "What is closely associated with a citizen being less likely to vote?",
        "options": [
            "Having a college education",
            "Being an older adult",
            "Having a lower income job",
            "Being a woman"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Having a lower income job"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was required by states under the 1993 National Voter Registration Act?",
        "options": [
            "It required states to demand proof of citizenship before allowing individuals to register to vote.",
            "It required states to allow citizens to register to vote when they sign up for driver’s licenses.",
            "It required states to allow driver’s licenses as identification for those registering to vote.",
            "It required states to allow individuals to register to vote at the same time they go to vote."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "It required states to allow citizens to register to vote when they sign up for driver’s licenses."
    },
    {
        "question": "A voter casts a ballot for a candidate based solely on the candidate’s previous vote on a tax cut. Which type of voting decision is demonstrated in this situation?",
        "options": [
            "Inspective",
            "Retrospective",
            "Introspective",
            "Prospective"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Retrospective"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is one method used by Southern states to restrict African American voting during the early 1960s?",
        "options": [
            "Property ownership requirements",
            "Godfather clauses",
            "Voter identification laws",
            "Literacy tests"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Literacy tests"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the impact of the Supreme Court’s decision in Plessy v. Ferguson?",
        "options": [
            "It allowed states to use literacy tests to determine eligibility to vote.",
            "It prohibited African Americans from holding elected offices.",
            "It prevented African Americans from serving on juries.",
            "It allowed racial segregation by establishing the 'separate but equal' doctrine."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "It allowed racial segregation by establishing the 'separate but equal' doctrine."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitutional amendment guarantees the right of a public trial and representation by an attorney?",
        "options": [
            "Sixth Amendment",
            "Fourth Amendment",
            "Eighth Amendment",
            "Fifth Amendment"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Sixth Amendment"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the focus of multiple amendments in the Bill of Rights?",
        "options": [
            "The rights of criminal defendants",
            "The rights of non-U.S. citizens",
            "The powers of the Supreme Court",
            "The powers of elected leaders"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "The rights of criminal defendants"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which types of cases would the Supreme Court use the standard of strict scrutiny?",
        "options": [
            "Cases that restrict fundamental rights of protected classes",
            "Cases concerning restrictions of rights against foreign nationals",
            "Cases related to workplace discrimination against women",
            "Cases involving discrimination against people with lower incomes"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Cases that restrict fundamental rights of protected classes"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which term is defined as a power of the government to take or use property for a public purpose?",
        "options": [
            "Constitutional right",
            "Voir dire",
            "Eminent domain",
            "Common law"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Eminent domain"
    },
    {
        "question": "What describes the Supreme Court's ruling in Mapp v. Ohio?",
        "options": [
            "Law enforcement officers are required to have a warrant for a search even if consent is given by the suspect.",
            "Law enforcement officers do not need a search warrant when using drug-sniffing dogs.",
            "Evidence obtained without a warrant falls under the exclusionary rule and is not admissible.",
            "Evidence obtained because it was in plain view is not admissible without a warrant"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Evidence obtained without a warrant falls under the exclusionary rule and is not admissible."
    },

    {
        "question": "Which amendment provides the rights for individuals to question those who testify against them and to call witnesses for their own defense?",
        "options": [
            "The Eighth Amendment",
            "The Fifth Amendment",
            "The Sixth Amendment",
            "The Fourth Amendment"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "The Sixth Amendment"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the U.S. Supreme Court's interpretation of the Fifth Amendment's right to due process mean for citizens?",
        "options": [
            "The government cannot limit the rights of citizens, except in the case that the Supreme Court gives the government authority over a specific right.",
            "The government must use consistent and fair procedures if it wants to limit a citizen's rights or seize private property.",
            "Citizens are protected from seizure of property by the government as long as they follow specific procedures to avoid it.",
            "Citizens have the right to dispute a court's decision if they do not agree with it, but the government ultimately determines guilt or innocence."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "The government must use consistent and fair procedures if it wants to limit a citizen's rights or seize private property."
    },
    {
        "question": "Why was the Supreme Court’s ruling in Brandenburg v. Ohio significant for freedom of speech?",
        "options": [
            "It extended federal protection for abstract discussions of violence and overthrow of the government.",
            "It limited federal protection for symbolic political speech, such as flag burning.",
            "It limited federal protection for obscene speech, such as pornographic magazines.",
            "It extended federal protection for defamatory speech, such as tabloid journalism."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "It extended federal protection for abstract discussions of violence and overthrow of the government."
    },
    {
        "question": "What describes the effect of the Supreme Court's ruling in Burwell v. Hobby Lobby Stores?",
        "options": [
            "Businesses do not have to provide employees access to birth control if it violates the business owner's religious beliefs.",
            "Businesses are not allowed to deny services to married same-sex couples that are provided to other married couples.",
            "States are not allowed to enact laws that make relationships between same-sex couples illegal.",
            "States cannot deny healthcare benefits to employees' same-sex marriage partners."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Businesses do not have to provide employees access to birth control if it violates the business owner's religious beliefs."
    },
    {
        "question": "What describes the Supreme Court's ruling in Texas v. Johnson?",
        "options": [
            "Fourteenth Amendment protections extend to all minority groups.",
            "Flag burning is constitutionally protected political speech.",
            "Laws banning same-sex relationships are unconstitutional.",
            "Nonthreatening hate speech is constitutionally protected."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Flag burning is constitutionally protected political speech."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is an aspect of the Supreme Court's Lemon test when determining whether a law violates the establishment clause?",
        "options": [
            "It must not be offensive to a major world religion.",
            "It must not inhibit nor advance a particular religious practice.",
            "It must uphold Judeo-Christian values.",
            "It must not make any reference to a deity or a higher power."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "It must not inhibit nor advance a particular religious practice."
    },
    {
        "question": "What was a result of Obergefell v. Hodges?",
        "options": [
            "It established the guiding principle for segregation until the 1950s.",
            "It affirmed the equal protection of same-sex couples under the Fifth Amendment.",
            "It upheld that the right to privacy included a woman's right to an abortion.",
            "It required that same-sex marriages be recognized across states."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "It required that same-sex marriages be recognized across states."
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the result of Roe v. Wade?",
        "options": [
            "It allowed Jim Crow laws to continue.",
            "It decided that segregated schools violated the Fourteenth Amendment.",
            "It affirmed the equal protection of same-sex couples under the Fifth Amendment.",
            "It upheld that the right to privacy included a woman's right to an abortion."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "It upheld that the right to privacy included a woman's right to an abortion."
    },
    {
        "question": "How did the Civil War Amendments affect individual rights in the United States?",
        "options": [
            "They restricted individual rights for men but expanded rights for women.",
            "They restricted individual rights by narrowing protections to men only.",
            "They expanded individual rights by extending protections to people of color.",
            "They expanded individual rights for people of color but restricted rights for people who were white."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "They expanded individual rights by extending protections to people of color."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is an appropriate characterization of media agenda setting?",
        "options": [
            "Agenda setting censors new stories that are unfavorable to sponsors.",
            "Agenda setting is based on modern meeting management practices.",
            "Agenda setting is an attempt to cover all news without limit.",
            "Agenda setting determines which events deserve public attention."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Agenda setting determines which events deserve public attention."
    },
    {
        "question": "What describes the principle of prior restraint?",
        "options": [
            "News agencies require permission from government officials before publishing stories.",
            "News agencies need court approval to publish stories about government corruption.",
            "The government can prevent some information from being published if it affects national security.",
            "The government can censor stories that could damage the country's reputation internationally."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "The government can prevent some information from being published if it affects national security."
    },

    {
        "question": "What describes the principle of prior restraint?",
        "options": [
            "News agencies require permission from government officials before publishing stories.",
            "News agencies need court approval to publish stories about government corruption.",
            "The government can prevent some information from being published if it affects national security.",
            "The government can censor stories that could damage the country's reputation internationally."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "The government can prevent some information from being published if it affects national security."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which legislation required the executive branch of the U.S. government to provide information requested by citizens?",
        "options": [
            "The Radio Act of 1927",
            "Branzburg v. Hayes (1972)",
            "The Freedom of Information Act",
            "Miller v. California (1973)"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "The Freedom of Information Act"
    },
    {
        "question": "How do presidents use mandates after an election?",
        "options": [
            "They use their new power to punish political rivals.",
            "They elect members of their party to local offices.",
            "They plan reelection for the next campaign immediately.",
            "They use their public support to implement campaign promises."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "They use their public support to implement campaign promises."
    },
    {
        "question": "Why is the Supreme Court affected less by public opinion than other government organizations?",
        "options": [
            "The justices hear cases people are familiar with.",
            "The justices are not elected but are appointed.",
            "The justices are elected by the Electoral College.",
            "The justices decide cases based on legislative support."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "The justices are not elected but are appointed."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is one common demographic group?",
        "options": ["Secondary employment", "Name", "Income", "Experience"],
        "correctAnswer": "Income"
    }
]
